Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Stop that!
Stop what?
I'm not doing anything.
Ow! That hurt.
Serves you right.
Will you cut that out?
I can't help myself.
You're almost as
sneaky as your father was.
He was the tomato
thief of all time.
I know what you're doing.
I'm hungry-
Let me finish dinner before you eat it.
Chop these.
Sorry. fellas.
Oh. Mom. tomorrow
night we're going with
Tiffany to buy a Christmas tree.
Okay. but a small one this year.
Watch your fingers.
No way. a big one. Ow! Shit!
Are you okay?
Yeah. it adds flavor.
Hello?
We don't want any.
Thea who?
I know it's Thea Brody.
How many grandkids do I have?
I can use the phone by myself.
I know you can use the phone by yourself.
You're a big girl.
I'm five years old now. Grandma.
I know you're five years old.
Hiya. kiddo. How're you doin'
down there in the sunshine?
I'm fine. Uncle Sean.
I went swimming today.
I'm taking lessons.
She already swims like a fish.
Hey. Michael!
Hey. bro.
The fish. Check it.
No way! You check it.
No. I'm on the phone.
Come on. let me talk to him.
Hello? I'm paying the call.
THEA". What's going on?
Your grandmother
is a slave driver!
Tell her to be nice to me.
Did you get the book I sent you?
Yeah. yeah. thanks a lot!
Hey. ask the big
doctor about his job.
Tough life. you Bahamian beach bum
playin' in the water all day.
I heard that.
He heard that.
Good.
Hey. how come you
get to leave early?
'Cause my desk is
closer to the door.
I don't think that's funny.
A big one.
A small one.
Your brother's
not gonna be here.
Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas. Jim.
Merry Christmas. Mary. Don't
forget eggnog time Thursday nighti
All right. we'll be there.
Okay.
We're getting a big
tree and we're getting out
all the old ornaments.
and we're gonna
do it right- And we're hanging
stockings on the mantle...
And we're putting out cookies...
And we'll have eggnog.
...and a bottle of beer for Santa.
All right!
All right. we'll do it all.
All right.
Tiffany. do you have any idea
what a madman you're marrying?
Yes. ldo.
I gotta go check in.
Okay.
See you later. Love you.
Bye. Me. too.
Don't be late!
Yeah. yeah. yeah. yeah. yeah.
That bad. huh?
We're out of decaf.
we're outta petty cash.
and we're outta
requisition forms.
Anything to do before I go home?
That man keeps calling
about his training film.
I can't convince him
we don't have a S.W.A.T. team.
Good night. Polly!
Amity Police Department.
Hold it!
There's an old dock piling
drifting in the channel.
Maybe it'll just keep on
drifting till it goes away?
It's stuck on a channel marker.
Good night. Polly.
Uh-huh.
It... Hold it!
Coast Guard's busy
and it has to be cleared
before the fishermen come back.
Where's Lenny?
Out to Ben Master's place.
Cow tipping.
Cow tipping?
Claims kids come by at night and
tip over his sleeping cows.
They're not givin' milk.
Okay. I'll take care of it.
Deputy Brody will take
care of it personally.
Call home.
tell 'em I'll be late.
Uh-huh.
Cow tipping!
The first Noel
The angels did say
Was to certain poor shepherds
In fields as they lay...
No. no. no. no. no! Hold it!
Hold m
Together. people!
Together. remember?
All right. Let's try it again.
Two. three.
Where the hell are the Wise Men?
Good luck. Harry.
I'm gonna need it
with this bunch.
Sounds better than
when I was a shepherd.
Joseph.
where the hell is your robe?
You're supposed to
be in costume! Jesus!
I'm over here!
In fields as they lay
In fields where they lay
Keeping their sheep
On a cold winter's
night that was so deep
Noel. Noel. Noel. Noel
Born is the King of Israel
All right. clear quickly.
Ready. angels. and...
Hark! The herald angels sing
"Glory to the new born King
"Peace on Earth and mercy mild
"God and sinners reconciled!"
Joyful. all ye nations rise
Join the triumph of the skies
With angelic host proclaim
"Christ is born in Bethlehem!"
Hark! The herald angels sing
"Glory to the new born King!"
Very good. people.
Very good.
And now. again. Noel. everyone.
Oh! Oh!
Oh! Oh. God!
Oh. God! Help!
Help me!
Oh. God! Help me!
Help! Help!
His things.
I thought you'd want them.
Grandma! Grandma!
We're here!
Grandma?
Mom?
We're here.
Thea. get down here. Come on.
Anybody home?
Michael.
Where's Mom?
She's been out there for hours.
How's she doing?
We've just come
from Tiffany's house.
Poor girl.
The doctors had to sedate her.
Hello. Mrs. Taft.
Hi. sweetheart.
I didn't recognize you. Thea.
You're so grown up.
Uncle Sean is dead. you know?
Will he ever come back?
We'll talk about
that some more later.
Would you like something to eat?
I had a hamburger on the plane.
MRS. Oh. POLLY: We
can do better than that.
How would you like
a funny bone sandwich?
How was the airplane ride?
Good. The lady
gave me two lollipops.
It came for him.
What?
It waited all this time.
and it came for him.
You guys must be starving.
I'll make some fettuccini.
Sit down. Ma.
I'm making dinner.
You should sit in here
and relax with Michael.
Really. Ellen.
there's nothing left to do.
I want you to get
out of the water.
What?
I want you to give
up that terrible job!
Come on.
Mom. you can't be serious.
Damn right. I'm serious.
I'm just getting started. We
just got our first grant last...
I don't want you
anywhere near the water.
Mom. you're upset.
Come on. just come on and sit down.
will you? We'll get there...
I don't want anyone in my
family anywhere near the water.
Never again. Never!
Hey. come on.
You can't believe that voodoo.
Sharks don't commit murder!
They don't pick out a person...
It picked out Sean.
It killed your father.
Dad died from a heart attack.
He died from fear.
The fear of it killed him.
Mom. Mom. Morn. Mom.
listen... listen to me.
There's never been a great
white where we live. ever.
It's warm water. They don't like it.
It's... It's...
Your brother's dead. Your father's dead.
It's too shallow.
It was a piece of wood!
It was a shitty piece of wood!
Michael!
He was just doing his job.
God. he could make
me laugh sometimes.
He was always taggin' after me
when we were kids. you know?
He always wanted
to do what I was...
Hey. where are you going?
Nowhere!
"To
everything there is a season.
"and a time to every
purpose under heaven.
"A time to be born
and a time to die.
"A time to plant.
"and a time to pluck up
that which is planted.
"A time to kill
and a time to heal.
"A time to break down
and a time to build up.
“A time to weep
and a time to laugh.
"A time to mourn
and a time to dance.
"A time to cast away stones
"and a time to
gather stones together.
"A time to embrace
"and a time to
refrain from embracing."
Hey. Tom. wait up!
Oh. you're gonna spoil her.
That's what grandmas are for.
Why don't you come down
to the islands with us?
I... I can't do that.
Come on. Come on. Mom.
No. No.
Get out of this cold. You can
spend some time with Thea.
Yes!
Come here. you.
Wanna know what I think?
I think it's a wonderful idea.
Yes.
Come on.
Morn. at least consider it.
I mean. you should get away.
You shouldn't be alone now.
Yes!
Great!
Yay!
If we hurry we can
catch the 4:30 ferry.
Today?
Today.
No. I... No. I can't.
Yes. you can.
Swing me. swing me!
Okay. okay.
Oh. my back! I can't do this.
I know. This is a tough one.
I'll take her. I'll take her.
Oh. my God. she's too heavy.
Help us. Daddy.
Okay. here we go.
Airplane ride.
Whoa!
And away we go. I know. I'm
gonna throw you overboard.
Oh. look!
Oh. hey. I always
wanted to ride one of those.
No way.
Chicken.
My mother always told me.
"if God had intended us
to ride parachutes for fun.
"we'd have been born
with free tickets."
I never said that.
Yes. you did. August 1977.
Where do you come
up with these ideas?
Where's the lady
who brings the soda?
They had them on the big plane.
There's some
coffee in the thermos.
I'm too young for coffee.
Oh.
Can I drive?
Thea!
Sometimes my father puts me in
his lap and lets rne steer the Jeep.
Don't bother Hoagie.
Sometimes I let
interesting people
sit in my lap and
steer the plane.
Oh. really?
Really.
Hoagie?
Yeah?
Jake tells me you're gonna have
to fly the rest of your life
to pay off what you
lost at the crap table?
Good news travels fast. huh.
I'll get it back next time.
How come it bumps up and
down when there's no road?
The wind does that.
You been to the Bahamas before?
No.
First time's
the best for everything.
After that. you know too much
and nothing's
ever quite the same.
What makes
the plane go up and down?
Oh. that's easy. You go like
this. and the houses get bigger.
Then you go like this.
and the houses get smaller.
Do you wanna go for a ride?
No! Yes!
Yeah!
No!
And so I'm
offering this simple phrase
To kids from one to 92
Although it's been said
Many times. many ways
Merry Christmas
To you
Kenny and Tamika are playing on the dock.
Hurry. hurry. hurry!
Everybody out!
Come on.
Kenny. Tamika!
I'm back! I'm home!
Hey. slow down.
Let me help you with
the bags there. Romeo.
Good.
you can take the heavy ones.
Thanks. buddy.
Grandma! Grandma!
Your room's in here.
Grandma. watch me! Grandma!
Thea. get down from there!
Grandma. watch me!
Get down from there!
Mommy lets me.
No. it's too dangerous!
Don't do that!
Grandma. watch me!
Come on. sweetheart.
But you always let me.
Not today. Come on. Thea.
The other kids are.
Daddy. why can't I?
Did you hear what I said?
Come inside the house right now!
No. I don't want to.
I wanna swing.
You can swing later!
Right now you have to unpack.
I didn't mean to start all this.
I feel like such a grandma.
Come on. I'll show you around.
Please. Mommy!
No! No! Put me down!
Will you stop making a scene?
Right now!
I want to play!
Kenny and Tamika...
I'll be all right. Michael.
Good. So will I.
She calls it
Tourist on the Loose.
The local government commissioned it.
It's for the public beach.
You forgot to stop at the store.
Oh. yeah. Yeah.
We need milk. bread...
There's a big unveiling
ceremony in a couple of weeks.
We need beer!
Okay. all right.
I'll be right there!
Pretty good. huh?
Yeah.
Grandma?
Will you stop fartin' around?
Michael. what the hell
you doin' down there. eh?
Jake. stop bustin' my chops.
Listen. you remember
what they look like?
They hard on the outside.
chewy on the inside.
Sometimes they come with a
little grime attached to them.
Move your ass. man!
Ah. bingo!
Good. How many you got?
Come on. Michael. talk to me.
Give me some numbers up here.
How many you got?
Leave me alone. Jake.
Oh. you're full of shit. man.
You been down
there all damn day.
we got nothin' to
show for it but excuses.
Michael. you're taggin' the
damn things. for Christ's sake.
I gotta separate the ladies
from the gentlemen first.
No. man. don't do that.
You move too slow.
You got two speeds.
slow and slower.
And if you move any damn slower
you're gonna grow roots!
Hold your water. Jake. Guess what!
The females have eggs.
Oh. great. So we're gonna stop
everything and pass out cigars now. huh?
Look. we're being paid to see where
they go. how they propagate.
I'm tryin to do it right.
Being paid...
If we had any decent funding.
I'd study their motor systems. I'd
take their temperature readings...
We're getting' it done.
That's bull. man.
We'd be able to do a
decent report for a change
and really give them something.
If you'd leave me alone.
I'd be able to do my work.
I know how to tag a damn conch.
Your readings suck. man.
Maybe it's the tags that suck.
No. no. it's I that made them.
Yeah. well.
it's I that put 'em on. man.
Then obviously
you put 'em on wrong. Michael.
No. no. no!
If you would've made 'em
right. it wouldn't happen.
They leak. A blind man
could find more conch
on the mountain side.
You can't find your
ass with both hands!
See. that's not fair. man!
You go away.
you leave me high and dry.
do all the work by myself.
you come back acting like a
zombie-It's Christmas Eve.
we're workin'
overtime 'cause of you!
Hey!
I'm sorry about
your brother. man.
Well. just...
Just take it easy. will ya?
Jake.
Come on. Jake. don't...
I don't want...
No!
Oh! Put me down. Put me down.
I missed you. man!
And then. he wrote dirty
words all over the garage.
He was... Your daddy was five.
He was your age.
I'm almost six.
Yes.
So is Jake.
Oh. look at that face.
Okay. do the other one.
Now. that's closer
to the real truth.
Oh. you. This guy was always getting
into some sort of mischief.
I got no doubt about that boy.
Was Uncle Sean ever bad?
Did you ever spank him?
Sharp shirt. Jake.
Hey. may your sex life
be as busy as your shirt.
Why. thank you.
My tea set! I got my tea set!
- Oh. let me see!
- Thank you.
Every lovely lady
should have a tea set.
Oh. this is a great present.
It has a teapot
and cups and saucers.
And a sugar bowl and a creamer.
Can I put real tea in it?
Yes. you can put real tea in it.
Can I make sandwiches?
Yes. you can make sandwiches.
Oh. Thea. you know what we forgot?
The Christmas carols.
Carol. the girl that works
down at the grocery store?
Oh. will you
stop it on Christmas?
Ah. ah. ah. ah.
Hark! The herald angels sing
"Glory to
the new born King..."
I miss him. Morn.
I want you to change your work.
Come on.
Mom. please don't start that.
You could teach.
you could write...
I'm not gonna quit now.
You're all I have left. I don't
want you working in the water.
"Glory to
the new born King..."
Mom. what I do
is perfectly safe.
At the moment.
we're collecting big snails.
Jake and I are scientists. you know?
We're almost PhDs.
We know what we're doing-There's...
There's nothing to worry about.
"Christ is born in Bethlehem!"
Oh. wait!
Next time don't keep me waiting.
Yeah. yeah. yeah.
And. well. we have to... We have
to dig the ditch really deep.
so the water'll go all the way
around and we can swim in it-
You're silly.
You know what? Let's pretend
this is Buckingham Palace.
And you'll be Princess Di. and
we'll have a parade with horses.
And you'll ride in a golden
carriage. and we'll...
And I can invite
Cinderella to the ball.
She'll come in
a golden carriage. too.
And we can have
cookies and punch and cake.
And I can invite
Prince Charlie and...
What's the name of
the other prince?
Grandma? Grandma?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Oh. we better get this done
before the tide comes in.
It's not nice to be evasive.
My mother says that
to my father all the time.
Hello. you two!
Hello.
I don't know why I fish here.
I never catch anything.
There must be a sign under the water.
"Beware. Hoagie's about".
You're the man who
drives the plane.
Flies the plane.
Mostly. it's like driving.
What's that? An excavation?
We're building a sand castle.
and you're invited for tea.
JAKE". You know why... You
know why you got no ambition?
Why is that. Jake?
That's what
happens when you lead a
sheltered Norman Rockwell life.
Norman Rockwell?
That's precisely
your problem. my friend.
You should talk. You weren't
exactly a deprived kid.
Think I buy that roots-rock-reggae
bullshit. forget it.
Cut that hair. and you're
nothing but a three-piece suit.
Save me from your ignorance.
Michael.
The bottom line is we got
three months left of work
and no money left to support it.
Spent it all on beer.
Bahamian Fisheries Department is
not exactly Fort Knox. my friend.
But. on the other hand.
Office of Naval Research.
they've got some money.
No. forget it.
What do you mean forget it. brother?
Money is money.
They put bombs on dolphins.
What? What kinda stuff
are you talking about?
I know a guy who got money
from them to study eels.
Ha! It's pretty hard
to put a bomb on an eel. man.
When I wanna hear from you.
I'll rattle your cage.
Michael. man. look at us.
We're out here bustin' our
bunghies to get our degrees.
I'm getting tired of
all this paradise shit.
It's getting on my
last and only nerve. man.
William.
What?
Look at you. boy.
What about me?
Man. you're a mental midget and
you're still reading all day.
You know. if mediocrity were
fattening. you'd all be whales.
And will you knock off
that stupid drummin'!
Oh. boy. look at you. man.
You've nothin' to clean.
What's wrong with
you anyway. Pop?
You think because you been to
university now you're smart?
VVatch it. buddy! Listen to you.
You'd like to...
I don't know why I've told
you all this. I hardly know you.
Sometimes talking to
a stranger is easier.
I can't explain it. It's just...
It's something I feel.
I always listen to my feelings.
I think I'm going crazy.
Nightmares and...
Maybe it was an accident.
It was no accident.
Well.
I'm not saying you're wrong.
I'm just saying that maybe
there are other possibilities.
When it killed Sean. I knew with
absolute certainty it had come for him-
I knew that!
I know it's coming.
What's it cost to take
a ride on that plane?
The water's coming in!
Depends on where you want to go.
Doesn't matter.
Hurry!
Just like that?
Just like that.
Oh! Oh. no! Oh! Oh!
Take the wheel!
I'm sorry.
What did you say?
Take the wheel.
No. I can't.
Sure. you can.
No. I mean. I...
I don't know how.
Nobody does till they learn.
What are you doing?
You better take the wheel or we'll
be swimming in five minutes.
Whoa. take it easy!
Take it easy!
Hold her gently.
She'll damn near fly herself.
See? Just like driving a car.
Where do I pull off the road?
No. you're doing fine.
I'll keep you out of trouble.
Relax.
Where are we going?
One time. I was flying
supplies up the Amazon
when I came down in the jungle.
You're not gonna
tell me. are you?
I was picked up by this
tribe of head-hunters.
and they took me
to see their chief.
You are impossible!
He took a long look at me
and he took me in his hut.
Inside his hut.
there was a long pole...
What is all this?
Just a little something
I arranged to cheer you up.
No. really.
What?
Tell me. what is all this?
It's a local festival.
It's called a Junkanoo.
Yeah. I
tell you. I'm not... I'm not
hearing anything up here. buddy.
How many have you tagged. exacfly?
How many?
Michael.
stop busting my bunghie.
Yeah. it's okay for you.
but not for me. huh?
Have no fear. Jake is here.
I just struck the mother lode.
I'm counting.
You better watch
yourself with that fancy
electrical
equipment down there. buddy.
Such a live wire is liable to
make your hair stick up funny.
That's good. Michael.
William?
Yeah.
there's no hope for that boy.
Jake? Jake. that's a joke.
Holy shit!
We got a big
fish down here. man.
Oh. yeah? How big?
Jesus!
Look out!
Shit!
What's wrong?
Ellen?
Jesus Christ!
Ellen. what's wrong?
Nothing. Nothing. I'm fine.
No. you're not.
I'm terrific.
Come on!
Give it up!
You can't keep doing this.
I can't keep doing this.
Hey. you promised me a drink.
Sharks come and go. Ellen.
People have got
nothing to do with it.
A drink with an umbrella in it.
Ellen. give it up.
Give it a kick in the ass.
Get on with your life.
I know what you've been through.
Don't worry.
The nightmares'll go away.
Give me my glasses. man.
Boy. I ain't never
seen nothin' so big. Never!
I was standin'
right next to Michael.
The blasted thing
went right past me!
Should've gone for you. Jake.
It was right over you.
Why did it come up?
What the hell's it doing
in warm water anyway. man?
What's the difference. man?
It's here.
It's only a shark. A great.
big. beautiful shark.
You two are makin' it
into somethin' it's not.
And it's ours. Don't say
anything to anyone. man.
Fishermen find out. they're gonna try
to kill it first thing you know. huh?
Michael.
we got us a great white.
Now. we gonna do some
real research. boy.
Do me a favor. will you? Don't... Don't
say anything about this to my mom.
Hey. man. I didn't mean to.
you know. flap my lips. eh?
- So...
- SO?
I said to him.
"Where's the disinfectant?"
He said.
"I've left it in town."
So I said.
"What are we gonna do?"
So he says.
"I'll tell you what we'll do.
"Come back at lunchtime. all the
flies will be in the kitchen."
Come to bed.
He took her sightseeing.
Well. you work. I work.
I mean. she needs someone to help
her take her mind off things.
I'll help you take your
mind off things. sailor.
It's soaking.
Thank you.
Good night.
Five minutes.
Louisa.
It's okay. It's all right. Jake.
I'll check on the table.
Okay. Okay. everything
rides-Everything rides.
Ooh. hey. it's Hoagie!
Hey. come on. I wanna see this.
Oh. that's Hoagie. all right.
Everything on the line.
You're not...
You're not betting it all?
All or nothing at all.
Here. Do you want to
throw the dice for me?
No!
Now get ready. Are you ready?
Oh!
I guess that's bad?
Depends on your point of view.
Ooh. look at that.
Come here to Daddy. girl!
All right!
Look at you.
You look great! And that dress!
Gorgeous!
It's on the house.
See? I knew there was a reason
I could afford all this.
Thank you. Shirley!
My father used
to say to me. "Jake...
"Jake. man. you got
two loves in your life.
"What you do and
who you're with."
Happy birthday. Louisa.
- Happy birthday.
- Happy birthday. Louisa!
And a happy New Year.
Happy New Year. everybody!
Happy New Year.
Don't go weak in the knees
on me tonight. boy.
You're gonna need all
the strength you got.
- Oh!
- All right. girl.
I knew a one-armed
piano player once.
took two minutes to
play the Minute Waltz.
You know. you oughta watch
how you talk to Michael and I.
We're about to be famous.
Hey. tell 'em about our discovery.
Jake!
No job talk. You promised.
You promised.
Right.
Would you risk
a dance with me. madam?
You'll be sorry.
So will you.
I have two right feet.
That's good.
'cause I have two left.
Well. that's a set.
A little quiet tonight.
New Year's blues?
No. No. not at all.
Come on. It's my party.
He's just Michael.
he's startin' to count them damn
conch in his sleep. you know?
Excuse me.
Mind if I Cut in?
Please.
The world would
be a better place
if more sons danced
with their mothers.
Michael. stop pouting.
You look like you
did when you were six
and didn't get
something you wanted.
I like him.
I enjoy his company-.
Yeah.
I don't like him
chasing around after you.
I don't trust him.
He's not chasing.
I'm not running.
You are being ridiculous.
Look. I've been a pain in
the ass and I'm sorry.
I'm not gonna bother you
anymore about your work.
You're not a pain in the ass.
Come on. let me finish.
I've been rehearsing
this all day.
Your brother's
death almost killed me.
I don't know.
I'll never get over it.
But I refuse to let myself
be run by an obsession.
I can't keep on
believing it was intentional.
I finally figured it out.
Good.
That's it. "Good"?
I thought you'd
break out the champagne.
No. I'm... I'm pleased.
Come on. Show your mother
what a good dancer you are.
Where is everybody?
Down here!
Where is Clarence and William?
I gave them the day off.
What for?
We got a job to finish.
Why are you
making a transmitter?
It's all part of
the master plan. Michael.
We're gonna test
it out right now.
We're gonna learn about its
motor systems. its heart rate.
We're going to study an
animal. a magnificent anima!
No one really
knows that much about.
As the sun slowly
sets in the west.
we bid a fond farewell
to the family of conch.
What the hell are
you talking about?
We write it up. wrap it up
and hand it in. brother.
Hey. how come your heart's so stronger
than mine. You got two of them?
Wait. we don't write up
anything until we're finished.
When I was a small boy.
my father said to me. "Jake...
"Jake. never do anything today
you can put off till tomorrow."
And them conch gonna
be there tomorrow. Michael.
Look. when we got the grant.
it was specified...
No. when I got the grant.
Okay. when I signed on. I...
When I invited you.
We got the grant together.
When we finally got
the grant together.
Look. we got three months'
work left on this thing.
We can't write a report.
We don't know enough.
Michael. we got a rare bird here.
You know that. huh?
Great white don't come down
to the Bahamas. never.
Never.
We supposed to let an opportunity
like that just swim away?
Look. my name goes
on the report. okay?
If it's a half-assed job. I don't get
my doctorate and neither do you.
I thought we were planning a
long. rosy future together. man.
So did I.
Hey! Hey!
Michael.
anybody home in there at all?
Man. you better beam down to
Earth with the rest of us.
Even if that shark's
still in the water.
it's not gonna be
there forever. you know?
It's gonna figure out the water's too warm.
It's gonna swim away.
Look me in the eyes. boy.
Tell me you don't want to study
that fish as much as I do.
Michael? Huh?
This is what we trained for.
This is what we
studied them damn books for.
Remember. my name
goes on that report. too.
It's as important to me
as it is to you. right?
All right.
you like them damn snails?
All right. all right.
I'll make you a deal.
Huh? Listen.
We study that shark.
just for a few days.
and it's back to
your lovely snails.
Now. that's fair. man.
That's fair.
Come on. indulge me with it. eh?
I don't know shit
about electronics.
Boy. you don't know
shit about anything.
It's time you learned.
I'll teach you how
to wear your hair.
I'll teach you how to dance.
Come on.
Teach you how to box.
Come on. follow me.
Get your butt down here. man.
This is the third time this month
you've forgotten to take it out.
I got a lot on my mind.
all right?
Does it take that much to
remember what day they come?
My brain is shrinking. You know.
there's only so much room
for fun things like garbage!
Oh. don't give me that
preoccupied scientist crap.
I'm trying to get ready for one of
the biggest events of my career.
Oh. yeah. okay.
Well. I thought artists
worked with their
subconscious. huh.
How come it's my responsibility?
Because.
Oh. Okay. nowl understand.
All you had to
do was explain it.
I take out the garbage...
Because.
Good. I'm glad we got
that straightened out.
We don't have
anything straightened out.
You're uptight about something.
What's wrong?
Why should there
be anything wrong?
I'm sitting around the house
enjoying my day off.
my wife starts yelling at me
about the garbage.
What the hell are
we arguing about?
I don't know. I...
I don't know.
Hey.
No fair. I'm not armed.
Then don't come any closer.
Turn it off. Off.
No.
I have work.
I've always wanted to make
love to an angry welder.
I've dreamed of nothing else
since I was a small boy.
Shut the door.
Uh-huh. Later.
Michael.
shut the door.
You sure
you've done this before?
Oh. yeah. lots of times. man.
Just trust your Uncle Jake. eh?
It's always worked. huh?
Well. uh. thus far.
Okay. take me out.
Little more.
There it is!
It's comin'! It's comin'!
You remember how
to pull rope. eh?
Yeah.
Yes. Jake! You got him. man!
Ah! Now would be a good time!
Did you see that. man?
All right.
let's try to follow it. yeah?
Now. we're gonna see if
Uncle Jake's equipment
is really working for us.
Michael!
Come on. move your ass. man!
Our little island
seems to agree with you.
I have my own little island.
Yet it's so cold in the winter.
I tried winter once-
Here we are.
Burlington. Vermont.
I flew a run to New York. Oh!
I have a bone in my left
foot that hasn't thawed yet.
When I was a small boy...
That is not hard to imagine.
by the way.
I dreamed of always being warm.
What do you want?
Whatever we had last time.
Two Bahama Mamas. please.
Stay awhile.
I'll take some time off.
You're always taking time off.
I like to travel. I'll nick
the boss' plane again.
Won't you get in trouble?
Not if he doesn't find out.
It's just a hop down to the Caribbean.
We'll spend a few days.
There must be a lot of
ladies who'd be glad to go.
Yeah. there are. but...
I've grown tired
of one-way conversations.
I have an irresistible
urge to kiss you. Ellen Brody.
Why?
Because it would
not occur to you why.
Blushing suits you.
Lord... I'm sorry.
It's nothing to be sorry about.
No. I mean. this whole thing...
The whole idea is preposterous.
I don't think so.
You sure you don't need glasses?
I'm a pilot.
My vision is perfect.
What are we getting
outta this old bucket?
What she's got. Nine knots.
Shit! We should be keeping
up with that damn shark.
You sure you got
the throttle open. man?
Wide open.
Come on. you overgrown goldfish!
Come to Uncle Jake.
How long have you known Hoagie?
What?
What the hell's
Hoagie got to do with this?
How long?
I don't know. Michael.
Since he got here.
Will you bring her to starboard.
When did he get here?
Who?
Hoagie!
Christ. man! One day he was
just here. that's all.
What do you know about him?
He's after my mother.
What's so funny about that?
You think he's not good enough
for your mother. eh?
But I agree.
Because if she was my mother.
I'd pack her up
and send her home right now.
Bring her about. we're going
in the wrong direction.
I mean. you know. some of these
pilots are flying drugs down here.
He's always going off somewhere...
You don't know.
Bring her about. Michael.
Now. bring her about. Now!
I am!
Hurry. man. we're losin' him!
Come on. you must know
something about him.
Christ. man!
He likes gambling.
he likes women. don't bother me!
I hear he flies
a lotta private charters.
Damn! We lost him!
Maybe your gear crapped out.
Maybe you crapped out. flappin'
your lips about Hoagie.
Maybe he's gone.
All right. Mr. Fish.
We'll come back and
find you tomorrow.
All he did was kiss me!
Well. that's a beginning.
A beginning of what?
To whatever happens next.
Oh.
I used to think that I'd be
able to handle these situations
once I was grown up. but I don't
even know if he's serious.
Mmm. give it some time. Ellen.
See what happens.
Well. part of me
wanted to go off with him.
I couldn't.
I don't know why he wants me.
Maybe he's got good taste.
Yeah. I don't think he's spent
much time with a woman like you.
I don't know what he thinks.
I don't know what I think.
I don't know why we're even talking
about this. This is so silly!
I mean. I feel too old to
be in this thing.
Oh. I hope not. I mean. I am
counting on a long. happy sex life.
You said it wasn't polite
to interrupt people.
Yes. I did.
It's time for tea. Grandma.
Oh. I almost forgot.
I didn't.
I put everything in my room.
My teddy bear's joining us.
Michael?
Michael. what is it?
Nothing. just a stupid dream.
Hmm.
Time for bed. peanut.
Oh. no!
Yep. Yep. Daddy's got homework.
But you let me last night.
Yeah. yeah.
Mommy's waiting to
read you a story.
Good night. sweetheart!
Good night. Daddy.
Good night. Grandma.
Night. Let's put up our feet
and shoot the breeze.
or whatever it is
beer drinkers do.
I... I got to put together what
we need for this report. Ma.
Jake always says.
"Don't do today what
"you can put off
till tomorrow."
Yeah. Jake's got a lot of those.
I'm leaving in a few clays. I don't
want to do that with you unhappy.
I'm not unhappy.
I saw you and Thea. You don't
know what it did to me.
You looked just
like your father.
Do you remember when you
guys used to imitate him?
Mom. I gotta get
this finished. okay?
I worry about you.
There's nothing to worry about.
I'm your mother. It's my job.
Just 'cause you're a man
doesn't mean I've retired.
I've worked on my smile.
It's... It's your turn.
That's better.
Blump. blump! Blump. blump!
Slump. blump! Blump. blump!
Jake. knock it off!
Blump. blump.
All right. just don't try
to renege on our deal.
We get a half
a day on the snails
and then half
a day on the shark.
You got 17 more
minutes down there.
then you're gonna come up here.
and we're gonna go
look for that shark.
Listen.
it's a big ocean. you know?
I mean. we could spend the rest
of our lives looking for it.
We're gonna find him.
Listen.
I got about a half a dozen.
I'm gonna tag 'em.
PH be right up.
You hearin' anything?
Nothin' at all.
Just another cool.
calm. tickly day in the Bahamas.
Just stay within a quarter mile.
I got a three-mile
radius on the monitor.
He come within three miles.
we should have
plenty of time to
beam your ugly ass up.
Michael. I got him.
Michael.
he's comin' towards you.
You better get out
of the water now.
All right.
I'm comin'. I'm comin'.
Shit!
Jake!
Michael! Michael!
Michael!
Michael. what's goin' on?
Michael. can you hear me?
Michael!
Son of a bitch! Oh. shit!
Jesus Christ!
It's over there!
Shit! Get the bang sticks.
we're goin' down.
Bang sticks are no good. man.
Goin' down. all of us!
Come on. come on! Michael!
Get him up! Get him up!
Watch his arm! Watch his arm!
Put him over here.
Lay him down gently.
Give me something for a tourniquet.
Gotta stop his bleeding. man-
Easy with you.
- Here. try this!
- Get that wet suit off.
Get the wet suit off.
I'll go get some disinfectant.
Keep cool. man.
don't worry about nothin'.
Michael. how are you?
It's under control.
I think he may be in shock.
Clarence. move it!
Hey. hey. hey. hey!
Hey. hey. what you doin'. man?
Nah. no one goes in the water
till we know where that fish is.
You fall off the horse. you get right
back on or you don't ride again.
What the hell? What kind of
bullcrap you talkin'? Huh?
Fallin' off a horse. man.
Anybody's supposed
to go back in the water.
it's me.
Jake. I'm gonna go down.
All right. so... What about Carla's gig?
It's almost time. man.
Michael. I can't just
let you go back down.
I'm scared shitless.
What the hell am
I supposed to do
if I can't go
back in that water?
All right. be careful.
Clarence. get up on that shack.
Give us some lookout
with them glasses. all right?
I hope the man
knows what he's doing.
Yeah. well. he's doin'
what he's got to do. eh.
Jake.
what's the monitor look like?
Are you gettin'
anything on the shark?
No. everything's cool.
You know. I'm thinkin' about yesterday.
It's probably all a mistake.
He was just hungry. You got
that tasty look. you know?
Yeah. but how come only me.
though. you know?
Maybe he just like white meat.
You're a funny guy. Jake.
Jesus!
"It is about
art that I wish to speak today.
"The raw material of
art surrounds us all.
"catching in the net that each
and every one of us casts
"into the current of life.
"But it takes the art..."
Where the hell are they?
They'll be here.
Can I go on the banana boat?
Margaret's going.
She's with her mother.
Okay.
Oh. boy! Oh. boy!
Thea. you be careful.
- I will. I will!
- Thea!
It's okay.
Banana boats are fun.
Oh. we should be so lucky-I wish
we were out there with her playin'.
Margaret. wait for me!
"Get to the point. man."
as my wife now says.
Okay. Well. in short. art is
grease for the wheel of life.
Today. we are privileged
to dedicate a work of art.
Carla Brody.
an artist of growing reputation.
was commissioned to express our
way of life in permanent form
to show the world what we all
know right here on this beach.
That it is
better in the Bahamas.
Absolutely.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Carla Brody!
Thank you. Commissioner
Witherspoon. Mrs. Witherspoon.
Thea!
Oh. my God!
Get out of the water!
Stop!
Come back! Bring her back!
Oh. my God!
Stop! Thea! Thea!
Thea!
Somebody do something!
No! No!
No! Oh. my God!
Oh! Oh. my God!
Mommy! Mommy!
Thea. are you all right?
Somebody get a doctor!
Get a doctor now!
Quickly!
I want my mom!
Hey. I'm sorry I missed you.
Where have you been?
What's the matter?
What happened?
Thea was attacked by a shark.
Oh. my God.
The doctor said she should be all right.
She's in shock.
Sweetheart? Sweetheart?
Oh. my God. I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I should've known. Jesus.
Should've known what?
We were trying to
keep track of it.
Of...
The shark.
The shark?
You knew?
Yeah. thought it went away.
Came after me yesterday.
She could've been killed.
You knew?
And you didn't tell us?
You let your mother think...
Where is she?
How could you do that?
Where's my mother?
Your own daughter'?
Where is my mother?
Why didn't you tell us?
Where's Jake?
Michael!
Jake!
What?
Come on! I need you! Hurry up!
Hoagie! Did you see our boat?
I just got here.
My mother took it.
I hope she's a good sailor.
A shark attacked
Thea and some kids.
She went after the damn thing.
She's gone after it?
Yeah. we gotta stop her.
You're going after her in that?
It'll take all
day in that bathtub.
You got a better idea. man?
I'll radio her position.
And the rescue boats will come
and pick her up. so don't worry.
She'll be fine. partner.
She'll never find that bloody
shark. man-We couldn't.
It'll find her.
What do you
mean. "it'll find her"?
She said it was coming.
What do you mean. "She
said it was coming"?
What do you know about it?
Well. she's got
the idea in her head
that the shark that killed Martin
and Sean is following the family.
Hey. he's not talkin'
about our shark. eh?
What do you do when
you're not flying people?
I deliver laundry.
Hold on. What's that?
Let's have a look.
Oh.
It's a big ocean out there.
Can't this thing go any faster?
If I go any faster. this thing'll
turn into a flying Cuisinart
and we'll be
diced into oblivion.
Come and get me.
you son of a bitch.
There she is.
That's her right there.
Is that what I think it is?
Mom...
Hold on!
Thomas. my boy. are you there?
This is Zero-Papa-Alpha here.
Hoagie. where the hell are you?
I'm 12 miles
southeast of Emerald Key.
Look for a ketch
called Neptune's Folly.
I need a coupla boats fast and somebody
who can kill a shark. a big one.
What're you doing?
I'm practicing landing.
Hang on to your socks. lads.
Hey! Wait a minute. man. You
sure you know how to do this?
Of course not! What kind of
pilot do you think I am?
Christ!
Hell. that wasn't half bad.
Get out of here.
I'll keep it busy.
No. it's gonna
come for the plane.
It's attracted to the electromagnetic
impulse of the metal on it.
Get the bloody hell out of here!
Michael!
Damn passengers! You're all the same.
Complain. complain...
Oh. shit!
Hoagie!
Hoagie! Hoagie!
Why...
Why'd you come out here?
Why did you bring him? Why?
Mom. Mom!
Why'd you take the boat?
It kept coming! Didn't you
realize what you were doing?
I had to do it.
There was nothing else to do.
Mom. you shouldn't have done it.
I tried to tell you.
I tried.
Hey! Give me a hand here.
for Christ's sake!
Hoagie!
How the hell did
you do that. man?
It wasn't easy. believe me.
Get him up. Get him up.
Quick. Got him!
Pull him up. Right.
You all right. man?
Oh!
Oh! Bloody hell.
Get it started! Double-time.
The breath on that thing!
You are alive!
Oh!
Let's get out of here.
Ellen Brody. Oh!
Good.
this thing's still working.
That's your engine. pal.
I'll have a look at it.
Oh. shit. he's close. man.
What is that sound?
That's the shark's heartbeat.
Hoagie. see if you can
get that thing finished. man.
Michael. give me a hand down here. man.
I got an idea.
We're taking water down here.
Ellen. start pumping here.
Ellen. get the bilge pump!
What's going on?
What do you need?
Take the transmitter
out on one of them radios
and hook it to this here strobe.
Just do it!
We gotta get the engine started!
Michael. just do it!
If that shark attacks us again
we're gonna feed that big
boy a meal he won't forget.
You better have something
good going over there.
We've got a rotten hose here.
There's a spare one
down there somewhere.
What you wanna do with this?
I'm riggin' the receiver.
If it works.
we get it inside that bastard
and then we set it off.
I got it. I got it. I got it.
We rig an antenna on this.
we got a slave unit
that'll shock
the hell out of him.
Right!
You're learning. partner.
He's getting closer!
They spend half their lives
looking for food.
and the other half eating it.
they don't care what it is.
Maybe he's got indigestion.
He's already eaten my plane!
It's not food he's after.
Michael. turn on your switch.
I wanna get a test here.
All right. anybody ever tell
you you're nuts?
All the time. partner.
This is all theory. though.
If it responds to external
electrical impulse.
it might respond
to one coming from inside it.
Confuse him. drive him crazy.
All right. give me a test.
Good.
You'd better get up here!
The heartbeat's stopped!
Shit.
Either he's gone or your
gear's crapped out again.
No. no. that's bull. man.
My equipment don't crap out.
He'll be back.
Get me the boat hook.
Maybe he had a heart attack.
Too much bloody food.
Humans are full of
cholesterol. you know?
Give me the hook.
Shit! Where the hell is he?
All right.
give me that line. Michael.
Right there.
There he is!
Ellen. try the engine.
Ellen. try to start the engine!
Come on!
Son of a bitch.
Let's get out of here.
No. it's too late. Hoagie.
He's gonna come for us.
Give me a hard port.
Right!
Here. give me that.
Come on.
No. look. this looks
bad here. No!
Michael. we have no time
for that thing!
Jake! Jake. you can't go out
there without a line!
Keep it steady.
It's gonna come back!
Damn thing's disappeared.
He's gone!
Jake!
We're taking too much water.
It'll stop the engine.
Ellen. take the wheel.
We've got to outrun it. Ellen!
That thing gonna work?
It'll work.
If Jake says it will work.
it will work.
This kinda charge
will drive it crazy.
Help!
Sweet Jesus.
we're headed straight for it!
Come about. Ellen!
Ellen. come about!
He's gonna hit us.
Hold on! Hold on!
Smile. you son of a bitch!
Michael!
Come over here.
It's all right! I'm okay!
Anybody alive?
Over here!
Jake!
Michael. you got a minute?
It's Jake!
Son of a bitch!
Jesus. Jake.
What took you so damn long. man?
What the hell are
you doing alive. huh?
I told you... I told you Uncle
Jake's equipment don't crap out. eh?
You're not going to do something
stupid like die on me. are you?
No. man.
I'm way too mean for that.
All right. here you go.
So from now on. we're going
to study snails. eh?
Yeah.
I want you all to come
to Amity this summer.
Yeah. we'll be there.
You make sure they come.
I will.
I'll miss you. Grandma.
Get in. Ellen Brody.
You'll miss your plane.
Goodbye. Grandma!
Bye. baby.
Okay.
Be careful.
Okay. See ya.
Take good care of Jake.
I will.
You gonna be okay?
Yeah.
Okay.
When I come back. remind me
to tell you about the time
I took 100 nuns to Nairobi.
There they were.
100 nuns. playing guitars
and singing. "The hills are
alive with the sound of music."
Then suddenly. one comes
up to me and she says.
"There's smoke
coming from the engine."
But I never took them seriously.
until they all started singing
Nearer. My God. to Thee.
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm